Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- middle aged, dark thick straight hair, bushy eyebrows, seated, suit, vest, tie [Futcher, Thomas Barnes, M.B., Associate Professor of Clinical Medicine] (Item 2354)
  this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Futcher" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- slightly off-profile view, prominent nose, middle aged, balding, white gray hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, suit, tie, seated holding book [Russell, William Wood, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Gynecology, JHU] (Item 2355)
- slightly off-profile view, prominent nose, middle aged, balding, white gray hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, suit, tie, seated with book on lap [Russell, William Wood, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Gynecology, JHU] (Item 2356)
  #2355, 2356 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Russell" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding, light colored hair, pince nez eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated at desk [Young, Hugh Hampton, M.D., Clinical Professor Urology] (Item 2357)
  #2357, 2358 same subject; subject is in "A book of Portraits.. ." JHU, but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, balding, light colored hair, pince nez eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated with book [Young, Hugh Hampton, M.D., Clinical Professor Urology] (Item 2358)
  #2357, 2358 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Young" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, white hair, mustache, round pince nez eyeglasses, suit, vest, tie, seated [Gilchrist, Thomas Caspar, M.D., M.R.C.S., L.S.A. {Eng.} Clinical Professor of Dermatology] (Item 2359)
  this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Gilchrist" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium light hair, parted, seated, suit, tie, holding book [Lord, Jere Williams, M.D., Clinical Professor of Dermatology, JHU] (Item 2360)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Lord" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, short light colored or gray hair, parted in middle, suit, vest, tie, holding open book [Thomas, Henry M., M.D., Clinical Professor of Neurology] (Item 2361)
- middle aged, short light colored or gray hair, parted in middle, suit, vest, tie, 3/4 view, holding book [Thomas, Henry M., M.D., Clinical Professor of Neurology] (Item 2362)
  #2026, 2027, 2035, 2039, 2040, 2361, 2362 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Thomas" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- older, white hair, mustache, seated at table with instruments, suit, vest, tie, smiling [Theobald, Samuel, M.D., Clinical Professor of Ophthalmology, JHU] (Item 2363)
  #2363, 2364 same subject
- older, white hair, mustache, seated at table with instruments, suit, vest, tie, smiling [Theobald, Samuel, M.D., Clinical Professor of Ophthalmology, JHU] (Item 2364)
  #2363, 2364 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Thayer" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- bald, dark eyebrows, mustache, little beard, jacket, vest, tie, seated with cigar [Cullen, Thomas Stephen, M.B., Professor of Clinical Gynecology] (Item 2365)
- bald, dark eyebrows, mustache, little beard, jacket, vest, tie, seated with cigar [Cullen, Thomas Stephen, M.B., Professor of Clinical Gynecology] (Item 2366)
  #1986, 1987, 2099, 2365, 2366 are same subject; subject is in "A Book of Portraits, JHU", this image appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, left hand of subject is circled in pencil for possible correction to exposure; mat and mount missing
- older, thinning medium light hair, parted on left side, mustache, round eyeglasses, striped suit, vest, tie, seated with open book at table [Finney, John Miller Turpin, M.D., Professor of Clinical Surgery, JHU] (Item 2367)
- older, thinning medium light hair, parted on left side, mustache, round eyeglasses, striped suit, vest, tie, seated with open book at table [Finney, John Miller Turpin, M.D., Professor of Clinical Surgery, JHU] (Item 2368)
  #2049, 2191, 2247, 2248, 2336, 2367, 2368, 2908 same image; subject is in "A Book of Portraits" this image appears to be a photogravure proof for the book; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, thick light hair, suit, vest, tie, with open book [Barker, Lewellys Franklin, M.D., LL.D, Professor of Clinical Medicine, JHU] (Item 2369)
  #2369, 2370 same subject; subject is in "A Book of Portraits.. " JHU, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, thick light hair, suit, vest, tie, with open book [Barker, Lewellys Franklin, M.D., LL.D, Professor of Clinical Medicine, JHU] (Item 2370)
  #2369, 2370 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Barker" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium dark hair, thinning, round eyeglasses, seated, striped suit, vest, tie, near table with microscope, holding cigarette [Hooker, Donald Russell, M.D., Associate Professor of Physiology, JHU] (Item 2371)
  #2371, 2372 same subject, subject is in JHU "A Book of Portraits", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium dark hair, thinning, round eyeglasses, seated, striped suit, vest, tie, near table with microscope [Hooker, Donald Russell, M.D., Associate Professor of Physiology, JHU] (Item 2372)
  #2371, 2372 same subject, this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Hooker" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- dark curly hair, standing in front of illustration of doctor with light attached to forehead looking down "patient's" throat, patient is drawn in cross section showing bones, organs, etc. [Broedel, Max, Associate Professor of Art as Applied to Medicine, Faculty of Medical Department, JHU] (Item 2373)
  #1087, 2017, 2373, 2374 same subject, subject is in JHU "Portraits", but not this image, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Hooker" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- dark curly hair, seated in front of illustration [Broedel, Max, Associate Professor of Art as Applied to Medicine, Faculty of Medical Department, JHU] (Item 2374)
  #1087, 2017, 2373, 2374 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Broedel" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- older, white curly hair, mustache, seated, dark suit, tie [Kelly, Howard Atwood, M.D., LL.D., Hon. F.R.C.S., Professor Emeritus of Gynecology] (Item 2375)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Kelly" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- older, seated in profile view, white balding hair, handlebar mustache and sideburns, eyeglasses, suit, tie [Hurd, Henry Mills, M.D., LL.D., Professor Emeritus of Psychiatry] (Item 2376)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Hurd" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- young, medium light straight hair, seated, writing [Weed, Lewis Hill, M.D., Professor of Anatomy] (Item 2377)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Weed" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, white gray hair, checked fabric suit, vest, tie, chrysanthemum boutonniere, black armband, seated, pad of paper on lap, holding eyeglasses in hands [Thayer, William Sydney, M.D., LL.D., Hon. F.R.C.P.I., Professor of Medicine] (Item 2378)
  #2378, 2382, 2734 same subject; subject is in "A Book of Portraits.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium dark curly hair, in bun, round eyeglasses, in suit jacket, seated at bench with microscope [Sabin, Florence Rena, M.D., Sc.D., Professor of Histology] (Item 2379)
  #2379-2381 same subject, subject is in "A Book of Portraits.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium dark curly hair, in bun, round eyeglasses, in suit jacket, seated at bench with microscope [Sabin, Florence Rena, M.D., Sc.D., Professor of Histology] (Item 2380)
- middle aged, medium dark curly hair, in bun, round eyeglasses, in knit cardigan sweater, blouse, seated at desk or table with papers, jar [Sabin, Florence Rena, M.D., Sc.D., Professor of Histology] (Item 2381)
  #2379-2381 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Sabin" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, white gray hair, checked fabric suit, vest, tie, chrysanthemum boutonniere, seated, right arm resting on desk with papers, pointing index finger [Thayer, William Sydney, M.D., LL.D., Hon. F.R.C.P.I., Professor of Medicine] (Item 2382)
  #2378, 2382, 2734 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Thayer" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium light hair, thin, parted on side, seated with open book in lap [Mac Callum, William George, M.D., Baxley Professor of Pathology, JHU] (Item 2383)
  #2383, 2384 same subject, subject is in JHU "A Book of Portraits" but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, medium light hair, thin, parted on side, seated at desk or table with paper, jars, suit, vest, tie [Mac Callum, William George, M.D., Baxley Professor of Pathology, JHU] (Item 2384)
  #2383, 2384 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Mac Callum" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, in lab coat, receding hairline, tie, standing at bench with beakers [Howland, John, M.D., Professor of Pediatrics, JHU] (Item 2385)
- middle aged, in lab coat, receding hairline, tie, standing at bench with beakers [Howland, John, M.D., Professor of Pediatrics, JHU] (Item 2386)
  #2018, 2168, 2273, 2385, 2386 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Howland" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- young, medium light hair, parted in middle, protruding ears, suit, vest, tie, seated at table or desk [Smith, Winford Henry, M.D., Ex-Officio {Supt., Johns Hopkins Hospital}] (Item 2387)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Sabin" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, salt and pepper mustache and pointy beard, seated, putting something in his jacket pocket [Meyer, Adolf, M.S., LL.D., Professor of Psychiatry, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2388)
  2065, 2067, 2388, 2389 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Meyer" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- dark thinning hair, salt and pepper mustache and pointy beard, seated with pencil and pad (?), jacket, vest, tie [Meyer, Adolf, M.S., LL.D., Professor of Psychiatry, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2389)
- middle aged, dark straight hair, parted, mustache, seated, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses, beakers on table, open notebook, holding pen [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU] (Item 2390)
- middle aged, dark straight hair, parted, mustache, seated, suit, vest, tie, round eyeglasses [Jones, Walter, Ph.D., Professor of Physiological Chemistry, JHU] (Item 2391)
  #1856-1865, 2390, 2391 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Jones" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- missing from box (Item 2392)
- middle aged, short medium dark hair, parted in middle, mustache, seated at table or desk, holding a pair of pince nez eyeglasses [Williams, John Whitridge, M.D., Sc.D., LL.D., Professor Obstetrics and Dean] (Item 2393)
  #2393, 2394 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Weed" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- middle aged, short medium dark hair, parted in middle, mustache, seated at table or desk [Williams, John Whitridge, M.D., Sc.D., LL.D., Professor Obstetrics and Dean] (Item 2394)
  #2393, 2394 same subject; subject is in "A book of Portraits.. ." JHU, but not this image, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, bald, white hair, mustache, trim beard, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie [Welch, William Henry, M.D., LL.D, Director and Head of the Department of Bacteriology and Immunology of School of Hygiene and Public Life] (Item 2395)
  #1988, 1989, 2395, 2403, 2404, 2953 same subject; subject is in the JHU Doctor's book, but not this image, mat and mount missing
- older, balding, salt and pepper hair, mustache, round eyeglasses, suit, high collar, standing, laboratory equipment on table at side [Abel, John J., M.D., Sc. D., Professor of Pharmacology, JHU] (Item 2396)
  #2066, 2397, 2396 same subject, this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Hooker" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- middle aged, mustache, beard, balding, long jacket, vest, tie, seated, with beakers, etc. on table [Abel, John J., M.D., Sc. D., Professor of Pharmacology, JHU] (Item 2397)
  subject is in "A book of Portraits.. ." JHU, but not this image, mat and mount missing
- standing at podium holding papers, jacket, tie, vest, white/gray hair parted on side, mustache, beard [Howell, William Henry, Ph.D., M.D., ScD., LL.D., Professor of Physiology and Assistant Director of the School of Hygiene and Public Health] (Item 2398)
  #2005-2007, 2022, 2249, 2250, 2274, 2275, 2398, 2399 same subject, this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Howell" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- seated holding papers, jacket, tie, vest, white/gray hair parted on side, mustache, beard [Howell, William Henry, Ph.D., M.D., ScD., LL.D., Professor of Physiology and Assistant Director of the School of Hygiene and Public Health] (Item 2399)
- salt and pepper hair, straight, parted, older, mustache, suit, high collared shirt, tie, seated, book in hand [Goodnow, Frank Johnson, LL.D., President of the University, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2400)
  #2062, 2400, 2401 same subject, this print appears to be a photogravure proof for the book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Goodnow" in DU's handwriting, mat and mount missing
- salt and pepper hair, straight, parted, older, mustache, suit, high collared shirt, tie, seated, book in hand [Goodnow, Frank Johnson, LL.D., President of the University, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2401)
  #2062, 2400, 2401 same subject, subject is in JHU "A Book of Portraits.. .", but not this image, mat and mount missing
- medium dark curly hair, jacket, vest, high collared shirt, watch chain, standing by open drawer of a file cabinet [Coy, George J., Registrar of the Medical Department, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2402)
- middle aged, bald, white hair, mustache, trim beard, stout, seated, in academic robes [Welch, William Henry, M.D., LL.D, Director and Head of the Department of Bacteriology and Immunology of School of Hygiene and Public Life] (Item 2403)
- middle aged, bald, white hair, mustache, trim beard, stout, seated, in academic robes [Welch, William Henry, M.D., LL.D, Director and Head of the Department of Bacteriology and Immunology of School of Hygiene and Public Life] (Item 2404)
  #1988, 1989, 2395, 2403, 2404, 2953 same subject; this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Weed" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- medium dark curly hair, jacket, vest, high collared shirt, watch chain, standing by open drawer of a file cabinet [Coy, George J., Registrar of the Medical Department, Johns Hopkins University] (Item 2405)
- middle aged, medium dark thin hair, suit, tie, seated in front of an x-ray (known then as a roentgen, named after W. K. Roentgen, their discoverer) [Baetjer, Frederick Henry, M.D., Associate Professor of Clinical Roentgenology] (Item 2406)
  this print is a photogravure, appears to be a printed proof or from book, various numbers in pencil on front and back of print, "Baetjer" in DU's handwriting; mat and mount missing
- missing from box (Item 2407)
- middle aged, bald, gray hair, mustache, stout, seated at desk or table with pen or pencil, suit, vest, tie [Butler, Nicholas Murray, President Columbia], 1918 (Item 2408)
  #1155, 1270, 1324, 2408, 2409, 3009 same subject; subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. ." but not this image; identification on back of mat in unknown hand
- middle aged, bald, gray hair, mustache, stout, seated, suit, vest, tie [Butler, Nicholas Murray, President Columbia], 1918 (Item 2409)
  #1155, 1270, 1324, 2408, 2409, 3009 same subject; subject is in "XXIV Portraits.. ." but not this image
- white hair, parted in middle, bushy eyebrows, herringbone suit [Holt, L. Emmett, Carpentier Professor of the Diseases of Children, Columbia Faculty], 1919 (Item 2410)
- middle aged, thinning medium light colored hair, mustache (?), suit, vest, tie, pince nez eyeglasses (Item 2411)
- middle aged, seated at table or desk, writing, suit, tie, round eyeglasses, balding light hair [Darrach, William, Professor of Clinical Surgery, Columbia], 1919 (Item 2412)
- middle aged, white straight hair, parted on side, mustache, beard, suit, vest, tie, seated with right arm resting on ledge (?) (Item 2413)
- bald, middle aged, pleasant looking, seated with pipe, suit, vest, tie, 1919 (Item 2414)
- young, smart looking, medium dark straight hair, parted on side, slicked down, suit, vest, seated (Item 2415)
- older, salt and pepper thinning hair, mustache, linen striped suit jacket, knit tie, seated with book (Item 2416)
- young, medium dark slicked-back hair, parted, suit vest, tie, seated holding unlit cigarette, looking down, pensive (Item 2417)
- older, standing, face in partial shadow, outside, white bushy mustache, in suit, vest, holding coat, no tie, tattered felt hat (Item 2418)
- middle aged, standing in front of anvil, holding hammer and piece iron, work shirt, suspenders, mustache, rumpled felt hat (Item 2419)
- older, heavy white and gray beard and mustache, sideburns, felt hat, overalls, denim jacket, seated, holding leather straps (Item 2420)
- older, lined face, beard, mustache, nubby fabric long sleeved shirt, suspenders, tattered felt hat, seated outside (Item 2421)
- young, smooth, dark or tanned complexion, work shirt, rolled up sleeves, overalls, cap (Item 2422)
  #2422, 2488 same subject
- older, somewhat heavy white curly hair, mustache, beard, polka dot shirt, holding pen knife and pipe (Item 2423)
  #2423, 2424, 2470, 2504, 2882-2884 same subject
- older, somewhat heavy white curly hair, mustache, beard, polka dot shirt (Item 2424)
- older, long straight white hair, parted on side, long sideburns and handlebar mustache, work shirt with full sleeves, seated, good felt hat in lap (Item 2425)
- older, thinning white hair, mustache, work shirt, vest, gaunt-looking, seated in hay (Item 2426)
  #2426, 2463, 2465-2467, 2480 same subject
- older, dapper-looking, heavy white and gray mustache, round eyeglasses, felt hat, vest, work shirt, leaning on fence, very thin physique (Item 2427)
  #2427, 2621 same subject
- older, heavy white and gray mustache, straw hat, vest, work shirt, knit cardigan, very thin physique, standing leaning on cane (Item 2428)
- middle aged, thinning white or light colored hair, mustache, stout, dark shirt and cardigan, standing in front of large wagon wheel (Item 2429)
- older, white hair and mustache, smartly dressed, suit jacket, vest, ribbon bow tie, seated on porch step with cane (?) or umbrella, minister (?) (Item 2430)
  #1620, 2430, 2431, 2609, 2795, 2796, 2825 same subject
- older, white hair and mustache, suit jacket, vest, bow tie, dark colored felt hat, seated (Item 2431)
  #2430, 2431, 2609, 2795, 2796 same subject
- middle aged, white hair, sideburns, beard; dark suit jacket, no tie, felt had, seated outside, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example) (Item 2432)
- middle aged, medium light hair, sideburns, beard; dark vest, no tie, felt hat, standing out side of barn door, sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example) (Item 2433)
  #2433, 2511 same subject
- young to middle aged, cap, dark or tanned complexion, work shirt, suspenders, cap, standing in front of or operating some kind machinery (Item 2434)
- older, very white straight hair parted on side, very long sideburns and beard, seated, light colored work shirt, suspenders (Item 2435)
  #2435, 2436 same subject
- older, very white straight hair parted on side, very long sideburns and beard, seated with book, light colored work shirt, suspenders (Item 2436)
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, seated holding rolled up newspaper (Item 2437)
  #2437-2439, 2841, 2845, 2846 same subject
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, standing holding folded newspaper (Item 2438)
- older, white beard and mustache, large, big brimmed felt hat, suit, ribbon bow tie, dapper-looking, seated holding rolled up newspaper (Item 2439)
- older, white and gray hair, parted in middle, beard and mustache, sideburns, seated, holding nice straw hat, smiling; sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example) (Item 2440)
- older, white and gray hair, beard and mustache, sideburns, felt hat, jacket, white work shirt, seated (Item 2441)
- older, white hair, very long beard and mustache, sideburns, tanned complexion, work shirt, suspenders (Item 2442)
- middle aged, large straw hat, dark work shirt, vest, striped pants, stooped on a wagon bed (?) with wood hand drill, drilling into what looks like a 2x3 (Item 2443)
- young, clean shaven, light colored hat, holding pipe in mouth, smiling, leaning on plank wall outside, paint peeling, work shirt, suspenders, belt (Item 2444)
- older, white beard and mustache, sideburns, large-brimmed straw hat, dark collarless jacket; sideburns and beard look like image identified as Mennonite man in Jacob's book (plate 28, page 179 for example) (Item 2445)
- middle aged, wit hair and mustache, cap, cigarette or cigar in mouth, work shirt, suspenders, apron, outside, unloading buckets of salt (?) from a wooden wagon (Item 2446)
- middle aged, short medium dark hair, cap, mustache, rugged complexion, dark work shirt, pants, suspenders, seated on a dock, ships in background (Item 2447)